# **LUIS GONZALEZ Data and AI Leader**

4549 W Stoneman Dr, Phoenix, AZ 85086 (623) 466-4172

luisagcenteno@gmail.com

# **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:**

Leading data teams through strategy and delivery that & Data Engineering Leadership drives business growth. Experience managing \$10M+ data technology portfolios and leading high-performing teams of 100+ associates. Visionary leader with 15+ years of 
Machine Learning, GenAl experience, empowering teams through challenges with a 🏈 Google Cloud, Azure, AWS fast pace and energy. Proven track record in mission Ø Databricks, Snowflake critical project delivery through team empowerment, technical acumen and awareness of industry trends.

Solutions Architecture

Financial Acumen

# **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

#### **PetSmart**

13 years 6 months

**Director Data Engineering and Architecture** | September, 2022 - Present

- Platform Modernization Migration of 1300+ workflows from on-prem IBM Netezza and Informatica Power Center to Google Cloud, Databricks and Snowflake.
- Machine Learning and AI AI Strategy implementation at PetSmart enabled at scale for the first time at PetSmart. Using MLFlow, Feature Store and Model Registry. Use cases such as Customer Lifetime Value, Propensity and Product Recommenders.
- Data Clean Rooms with Snowflake Samooha for Audience Overlap, Marketing attribution and Look Alike Audiences for incremental revenue of \$40M+
- Customer Identity Strategy Personalization and marketing efficiency with cost savings of \$20M+ and revenue lift of \$50M+ through increased conversion and improved CRM engagement with our 35M+ active members.
- Platform Cost Optimization. Data Technology Strategy allows efficient management of our platforms value/cost. Established FinOps process
- Evolved Data Engineering practices to use industry standard patterns to create reusable Data Products
- Budget accountability and contract negotiation for Data Technology stack (\$10M+ annually) including Google Cloud, Databricks, Snowflake, MicroStrategy, ThoughtSpot, Tableau, TIBCO, MuleSoft, Denodo, IBM Netezza, MDM, Informatica, Alteryx

## Sr Manager Data Architecture | April 2021 - October 2022 (1 year 7 months)

- MarTech Implementation of SalesForce Marketing Cloud platform. Redesigned Customer Journey and migration from Oracle Responsys, Vibes and Urban Airship to simplify MarTech ecosystem
- Built a Composable Platforms to scale Marketing Audience Segmentation through Databricks, Snowflake and HighTouch
- Enabled ML models for Personalization and Campaign Measurement
- Automated Data Subject Rights Privacy Compliance by implementing Data Governance principles
- Delivered modernization of Point of Sale and Finance (SAP-based) applications through the use of data platforms
- Matured Data Architecture through the creation of a **Center of Excellence** and led data transformation at PetSmart through the use of patterns and best practices

# EIM Delivery Manager | April 2018 - April 2021 (3 years 1 month)

- Established Operational BI in 1700+ Stores and Grooming salons, 400+ PetsHotels and 14 DCs with MicroStrategy mobile
- Project Estimation and planning through creating a repeatable blueprinting process that yielded a +/-5% project cost variance.
- Implemented an Enterprise Resource and Capacity Planning Management tool to maximize productivity and minimize project onboarding time

# EIM Delivery Lead | November 2015 - April 2018 ( 2 years 6 months)

- Led Development teams in charge of BI Reports, Analytics and Data delivery.
- Establish and govern development standards on EAI, DataWarehouse and BI platform.
- Talent development opportunities for internal staff.

# **Software Engineer** | December 2012 - November 2015 (3 years)

- Integration with TIBCO BW and EMS. Python, Java, MicroStrategy, Informatica, Netezza
- Define company standards in compliance with EA principles and standards.
- Improved data quality and project delivery speed through design patterns, best practices and development standards. Peer reviews and approvals

#### **MGM Resorts International**

May 2012 - December 2012 (8 months)

# **Senior Enterprise Architect**

- Accountable for end to end accountability in Financial applications for Hotel, Ticketing, Restaurants and other real-time applications from design through implementation to deployment and monitoring.
- Created application landscape view within larger architecture context.
- Defined application integration architecture standards.

## **EDUCATION:**

## Master's Degree, Information Technology Management

Instituto Technologico de Monterrey | 2014 - 2017

#### **Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science Engineering**

Instituto Technologico de Pachuca | 2002 - 2007

# **Computer Science Technician**

CBTis 222 | 1999 - 2002

#### **CERTIFICATION:**

## **Databricks Certified Data Engineer Associate**

Databricks | 2023

#### **MicroStrategy Certified Analyst**

MicroStrategy | 2020

#### **Project Management Professional**

Project Management Institute | 2018

# **MuleSoft Certified Developer**

MuleSoft | 2015

## **TIBCO Certified Professional for BusinessWorks 5**

TIBCO | 2011

# **Oracle Certified Web Components Developer 5**

Oracle | August 2010

# Sun Certified Java Programmer 6

Sun MicroSystems | 2009